Fact Book UP128
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Fact Book
1973 -- 2020
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of Institutional Research and Evaluation
UP128
0.25 Linear Feet
42 Volumes
1 Artifact(s)
58 Digital Object(s)
1 Gigabytes Of the 58 digital objects in this collection, 49 have extent information and comprise 1 GB of data.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Fact Book; and Fast Facts Abridged Fact Book.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of Institutional Planning was founded under the direction of John (Jack) A. Dunn Jr. in 1977. Dunn began publishing the University Fact Book in 1973 while he was Special Assistant for Administration in the Office of the President. In 1977, Dunn was named the Associate Vice President of Planning and the Office of Institutional Planning assumed the responsibility of publishing the University Fact Book, under Dunn's direction. The office changed its name to the Office of Institutional Research in 1989 and began conducting admissions studies. It changed its name again to the Office of Institutional Research and Evaluation in 2006.
The Office of Institutional Research and Evaluation is responsible for providing research data and information to a variety of decision makers and departments within Tufts University. Along with preparing a range of research survey projects, outcome assessments, and program evaluations, the Office also publishes the University Fact Book and the University Dashboard. Staff members also conduct consultative work in the areas of designing surveys, crafting research proposals, and preparing evaluations.
Related Materials
UA042, Office of Institutional Research and Evaluation, DCA.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues of the Fact Book starting in 1973. The Tufts University Fact Book is researched, created, and published by the Office of Institutional Research of Tufts University. The Fact Book includes annual facts, figures, and statistics of the university.
- Fact Book, 1973 -- 2020; UP128.001; 42 Volumes; 1 Artifact(s); 53 Digital Object(s); 1 Gigabytes Of the 53 digital objects in this series, 46 have extent information and comprise 1 GB of data.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the Tufts University Fact Book which is researched, created, and published by the Office of Institutional Research of Tufts University. The Fact Book includes annual facts, figures, and statistics of the university. This series also contains a log of changes made to the Fact Book after it went to press.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts University fact book, 1973; UP128.001.001.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 1)
    Office of Institutional Research
  - Tufts University fact book, 1974; UP128.001.002.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 2)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1975; UP128.001.003.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 3)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1976 -- 1977; UP128.001.004.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 4)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1977 -- 1978; UP128.001.005.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 5)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1978 -- 1979; UP128.001.006.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 6)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1979 -- 1980; UP128.001.007.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 7)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1980 -- 1981; UP128.001.008.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1981 -- 1982; UP128.001.009.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1982 -- 1983; UP128.001.010.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 39 Megabytes (Box Volume 10)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1983 -- 1984; UP128.001.011.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 41 Megabytes (Box Volume 11)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1984 -- 1985; UP128.001.012.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 43 Megabytes (Box Volume 12)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1985 -- 1986; UP128.001.013.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 46 Megabytes (Box Volume 13)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1986 -- 1987; UP128.001.014.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 48 Megabytes (Box Volume 14)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1987 -- 1988; UP128.001.015.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 50 Megabytes (Box Volume 15)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1988 -- 1989; UP128.001.016.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 49 Digital Object(s) (Box Volume 16)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1989 -- 1990; UP128.001.017.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 54 Megabytes (Box Volume 17)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1990 -- 1991; UP128.001.018.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 58 Megabytes (Box Volume 18)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1991 -- 1992; UP128.001.019.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 58 Megabytes (Box Volume 19)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1992 -- 1993; UP128.001.020.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 63 Megabytes (Box Volume 20)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1993 -- 1994; UP128.001.021.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 65 Megabytes (Box Volume 21)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1994 -- 1995; UP128.001.022.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 68 Megabytes (Box Volume 22)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1995 -- 1996; UP128.001.023.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 68 Megabytes (Box Volume 23)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1996 -- 1997; UP128.001.024.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 69 Megabytes (Box Volume 24)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1997 -- 1998; UP128.001.025.00001; Office of Institutional Research; 1 Digital Object(s); 56 Megabytes (Box Volume 25)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1998 -- 1999; UP128.001.026.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 50 Megabytes (Box Volume 26)
  - Tufts University fact book, 1999 -- 2000; UP128.001.027.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 43 Megabytes (Box Volume 27)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2000-01-01; UP128.001.028.00001 (Box Volume 28)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2001-02-01; UP128.001.029.00001 (Box Volume 29)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2002-03-01; UP128.001.030.00001 (Box Volume 30)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2003-04-01; UP128.001.031.00001 (Box Volume 31)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2004-05-01; UP128.001.032.00001 (Box Volume 32)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2005-06-01; UP128.001.033.00001 (Box Volume 33)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2006 -- 2007; UP128.001.034.00001 (Box Volume 34)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2007 -- 2008; UP128.001.035.00001 (Box Volume 35)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2008 -- 2009; UP128.001.036.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box data_value_missing_71e5c52dc520f29048346489a9fff8e3)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2009 -- 2010; UP128.001.037.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box data_value_missing_71e5c52dc520f29048346489a9fff8e3)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2010 -- 2011; UP128.001.038.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 38)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2011 -- 2012; UP128.001.039.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 39)
  - Log of changes made to the 2011-2012 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000058; 83.4 Kilobytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2012 -- 2013; UP128.001.040.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 40, Box Shared 10)
  - Log of changes made to the 2012-2013 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000059; 71.5 Kilobytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2013 -- 2014; UP128.001.041.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box data_value_missing_92a934966c6e533e45cad7d81ce2e4dd)
  - Log of changes made to the 2013-2014 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000060; 5.1 Megabytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2011 -- 2012; UP128.001.042.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box data_value_missing_92a934966c6e533e45cad7d81ce2e4dd)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2014 -- 2015; UP128.001.043.00001; Office of Institutional Research (Box Volume 43)
  - Log of changes made to the 2014-2015 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000061; 15 Megabytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2015 -- 2016; UP128.001.044.00001; 1 Volumes (Volume 44)
  - Log of changes made to the 2015-2016 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000062; 13.4 Kilobytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2016 -- 2017; UP128.001.045.00001; 1 Volumes (Volume 45)
  - Log of changes made to the 2016-2017 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000063; 118.5 Kilobytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2017 -- 2018; UP128.001.046.00001; 1 Volumes (Volume 46)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred by the Office of Institutional Research and Evaluation, 2018, accession UP-2018-058.
  - Log of changes made to the 2017-2018 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000064; 15.7 Kilobytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2018 -- 2019; UP128.000065; 9.2 Megabytes
  - Log of changes made to the 2018-2019 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000066; 268.5 Kilobytes
  - Tufts University Fact Book, 2019 -- 2020; UP128.000067; 3.2 Megabytes
  - Log of changes made to the 2019-2020 Fact Book after going to press, UP128.000068; 56.8 Megabytes
- Fast Facts Abridged Fact Book, 2005 -- 2011; UP128.002; 0.25 Linear Feet; 5 Digital Object(s); 10.3 Megabytes Of the five digital objects in this series, three have extent information and comprise 10.3 MBs of data.
  Tufts University Fast Facts Abridged Fact Book is designed as a quick reference guide to the information contained in the Tufts University Fact Book. This overview consists of the data that was collected from various university departments for that publication.
  - The Abridged Factbook, 2005 -- 2006; UP128.002.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Abridged Fact Book, 2006 -- 2007; UP128.002.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, Abridged, 2006 -- 2007; UP128.000069; 4.5 Megabytes
  - Abridged Fact Book, 2007 -- 2008; UP128.002.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University Fact Book, Abridged Version, 2007 -- 2008; UP128.000056; 2.3 Megabytes
  - Abridged Fact Book, 2008 -- 2009; UP128.002.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Tufts University Abridged Fact Book, 2008 -- 2009; UP128.000057; 3.5 Megabytes
  - Abridged Fact Book, 2009 -- 2010; UP128.002.001.00005
  - Abridged Fact Book, 2010 -- 2011; UP128.002.001.00006